in this video we're going to talk about
executors and what are executors? executors
are physical keys buttons knobs faders you can
find on the GrandMA 3 hardware they can also
be represented as on-screen virtual executors and
can be viewed and operated in the playback window
if you want to know how it works be sure to
watch the video all the way to the end as i will
go through all the different functionalities you
can find in the GrandMA 3 console and the keys and
all the faders and buttons and configuration
of those but how do we work with them how do
we assign sequences to them and what else
can we do with them so let's start here and
and look at the screen here if you don't have
this window here if you push this little button
right down here you will open the uh the overview
of the executors of of the first 10 faders on your
console and the first 10 faders right here is
or the first 10 sections because it's not only
the faders now on the GrandMA 2  you would
have a fader below that fader you would have
a button and above that fader you would have
two buttons those four items were tied together
if you stored something on your fader those
two buttons on top of the button underneath
would be one and the same thing a roll manipulate
the same cue list or whatever you had on your
fader the bottom row on the GrandMA 2 was
on its own and you could store stuff on that
independently on what you did on the on the
faders the GrandMA 3 changed up a little
bit now you have rows here you have a row 101
201, 301 and 401 as you can see in this window
101 represents the bottom row down here below the
faders 201 represents the next row here and they
are tied into the fader i'm going to show you this
in a minute but 201 and the fader is basically one
and the same thing you can have one function here
and of course you can turn the fader up and down
301 is this button up here and the first knob
you can find right here and 401 is the same
it's the button here and the rotary knob on the
on top of it but how does this work how can we
manipulate it how can we store cue lists to our
sequences to to the faders and how can we have the
go buttons we want the go minus button we want the
top button we want the flash button we want that's
a kind of a different way and a different approach
that that we used to have in the GrandMA 2 but
let me show you right here we have the playback
window up here as we built last time and as you
can see here i deleted all my sequences and we are
ready to build some new ones so let's just build
a sequence here with all our vipers in our let's
say our position number one at full we give it a
magenta color and we store this in sequence number
one we name the sequence again we just call it
master cue list there we go as i showed you in the
last tutorial you can simply assign this cue list
by writing a sign down here remember your
shortcuts down here if your shortcuts are active
you can simply use the the shortcut menu which
is pretty powerful so assign the master cue list
to 201 now we assigned our cue list here to the
bottom button down here in the bottom and the
first fader and that's it these buttons on top
and the button below it is not tied into this
one yet but we can do that if we want to to be
able to do that we have to go in and manipulate
whatever is going on on our screen here so if
we press here where it says master cue list
this window opens and if this
window doesn't open the same way on
on your machine as it does on mine it's because
i set it to window number two screen number two
right here and then and then when i open it i
can simply say where do i want it to open so if
it opens on screen number one you can simply
say i want it to open on screen number two
let me show you real quick to be able to
manipulate what's going on in this cue list
or maybe extend it and make use of the other
buttons and rotary knobs on this fader on this
sequence you can simply go into master cue list
here and push it it opens up a new window but to
be able to compare it to what we're doing we need
it to open in another window so if we go up here
into the small screen here you push it and you say
i wanted to open on internal screen number two you
push that one and it opens in its own window it's
probably going to open if you have two screens
it's probably going to open on the other screen
so you basically just take it over here and
then we can see what we're doing we store our
cue list here on number 201 this is the 200
range here if you store the next cue list on this
one it's gonna be in this row right here so let's
do some manipulation we can extend the cue
list and say right now i want to make use
of the button above it which is this button and
this rotary knob up here so i can just push this
one and as you can see this extends the cue list
or the sequence to the next row of buttons and
now we can make use of the button above it and
the rotary knob above it if we want to we can
do it again and say i want even more room and
we can push to 400 and it goes all the way up
we can't choose the one below it for some
reason but what we can do is we just close
this window down again we simply delete the cue
list right here and instead of assigning it to
201 we can simply assign it to 101 and if we go
into the cue list again now we can extend it up
and make use of stuff above it so it starts
from the bottom and it goes all the way up
you can actually extend it to the side as well
if you want to and then have even more buttons
to manipulate if you want some learn learn buttons
or whatever macros or something between it here
that's also possible and you can do that if you
want some more functionality some more buttons
to make use of we're not going to do this in
this case to delete this row we just extended
it to just press the one again this is the way it
functions this is the way it works press number
two it extends to your your right number three
it extends to your right and back down if you
just check it that way and then delete it that way
so now we have the 100 range which is the bottom
button the 200 range which is the next button
and the fader and we can extend it up into the
300 range which is the next row of buttons and so
on so let's say okay what do we want to do here
i would like this one to go to the top of my cue
list say i have 10 cues with all my colors in
for instance i would like this one to go to the
first cue so i push it and set it to top and
that's the way it's going to work now the next
one is my go plus and for some reason i want my
bottom one to be go plus and the next one to be
go minus so we choose that one and say go minus
so let's just close this down and see where we're
at right now we have our master cue list here and
we have our top button and we have our go minus
and we have our goplus to be able to see a little
bit better i actually built a different view so we
can go into our faders and buttons here and this
extends the playback window so we can better see
what's going on we have our fader here we can take
it up and down we have our rotary knob we have
the top button and go plus and go minus button
down here let's just clear what we put in the
programmer before so let's build a few extra cues
i choose all my vipers i put them into white and
into the audience for instance i store this on my
master cue list and i create my second cue as we
talked about in the last episode let's do it again
and say i need a cyan color and i put it into my
position one and i store this as cue number three
so there we go we now have three cues in our cue
lists so let's just clear out here and say now we
have our go minus and go plus we are currently in
cue number one i can say go plus to cue number
two go plus to cue number three and then it goes
all the way back but if i go into cue number two
and say we have ten cues here and i just want to
go up to the top where my white color is or open
white color i can just push the top button and it
goes straight up regardless of how many cues there
there is in it we can also assign the rotary knob
to do different things so let's just go back into
our setup window here and say my encoder
left i want this to be a go minus button
and you can see it recognizes it over here my
encoder to the right needs to be a go plus button
for instance so here we go now we have the option
of turning your cues up and down with the rotary
knob and we can even go further and say if we put
something down here this is what it does when the
rotary knob is rotated but pushed down at the
same time but let's not do that in this episode
you can also change the functionality of your
master if you wanted to be for instance a temp
fader or let's just put it back to master again
but there is about a gazillion different options
in here in the settings of every sequence but
that's for a different tutorial right now you can
check out one of the other videos from our channel
they are linked on the screen right now and please
like the video and maybe even subscribe to the
channel if you don't want to miss any future
episodes from us thank you for watching this time
and i hope you'll check out the next video bye